From slicing, we move to data structure, also
known as collection data types, which are
types of lists stored inside of variables.
You have seen how indexing and slicing work
with items in a list, but we have yet to cover
how to build a list.
We will do that in the next topic.
This topic will look at three other data types:
tuples, sets, and dictionaries.
I want you to really focus on two pieces from
each type: what the structure does and the
syntax used to build each structure.
Strings themselves are data structures as
they are collections of characters.
Dictionaries store data in key-value pairs.
If, for example, you have a game where you
have a point value for each type of coin someone
earns based on answering a question, you could
set up a key-value pair list for those coins,
as we have on lines 1 through 6 of this 124-structure
file.
Notice that the collection of key-value pairs
is inside curly brackets, and the syntax goes
key: value.
In printing this dictionary, as the code on
line 7 does, we see the complete set of keys,
the coins, and their values.
A set is a type of collection that stores
unique values of data.
On line 10, I have started a list with three
regions, and the command to print the list
is on line 12.
Watch what happens when I try to add a duplicate
value by typing regions.add(“east”)
on line 11 and then run the code.
We don’t get any errors, which is good,
but East is not in the list twice because,
as mentioned, each value in this type of list
is unique.
However, if I change this value to add West
and then rerun the code, the value is added
as it is a unique value compared to the rest
of the existing values in the set.
Lastly, we have tuples, which is a list with
immutable values.
You may hear the word immutable often with
values in programming.
Immutable means unchangeable, as the only
way to change what is in a variable is to
redeclare the variable.
Case in point: I have a tuple, on line 15,
with a game character’s name and animal
type.
If I try to change the second value, index
1, to another animal
and run this code, an error message indicates
that we cannot assign a new value to that
index because tuples are immutable, as we
just said.
Tuples are good for lists that should not
have their items changed.
Knowing which type of data structure to use,
given a situation, makes apps perform more
smoothly, as some data structures are meant
to have unique values, protecting from duplicate
data.
Some structures are intended to be immutable,
and some need to store data in key-value pairs.